[Music]
foreign
advanced level training
so this is our lesson two in our
Advanced Training but it's a lesson 17
if you consider as overall present is
Task of automation Concepts
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you
how can we create
and how can you execute your execution
lists by using latest version try
sentence Tasker 16. please do subscribe
to the channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you
okay so by end of this lesson
you're gonna learn how to create
execution lists
and then you will be able to link your
automated test cases to the execution
list
and then you can interpret the execution
results
okay so whenever once you complete
automating your test case you no longer
need to run in scratchbook
because in our previous sessions we used
to run in the scratchbook so running in
the scratchbook is just to just for the
trial runs to make sure your automated
test cases will work
but for proper test case execution the
recommendation is to use your execution
lists where it stores all the results
and history of your
test runs
okay so now let's jump onto the system
and understand how can we create and
execute our execution lists
so this is my Tasker tool right so till
date we were talking about the test
cases module right I have already
um
teach you about the modules how to
create modules and then we also worked
on test cases so these two sections we
already worked on now for execution to
create execution lists we'll start
working on the new section called
execution so you need to navigate to
execution section
and under execution section
under execution lists
right click and let's create a new
foreign
list folder okay so basically let's
create a execution folder okay
let's name this as
Ian zero two
execution
create execution list okay
create
execution list
okay under this
execution folder again right click and
now let's create
execution list okay this is your
execution list this is your execution
list folder okay let's create execution
list
and name this as
shopping
cart okay shopping cart
so now
once you create your execution list
now it's time for us to map the test
cases that you would like to execute as
part of this execution list okay so for
that let's drag this test cases folder
and put this at the right side
okay and now
let's go to execution here
so let's say I have completed authoring
I mean automating the test cases okay so
as soon as you complete automating the
test cases let's assume uh session
actual action modes okay this automation
is done so that's why what we are going
to do we are going to mark this work
state as completed
and also let's also Mark this one also
as completed okay
and let's mark this also as completed
okay
okay so now
so once you mark the test case
automation has completed now let's say I
want to execute the test cases
of these two test cases okay for that
let's map this test case
to the execution list what I created for
that you need to drag and drop
onto the execution list that we created
and then let me drag this also and drop
so now if you see we already
created both I mean we already linked
two test cases from two different
sections right two different sessions
so now sorry let me just rename this as
okay this is my exhibitionist right so
and
if you see here
if you want to okay if you want to
let me explain if you want to exclude
any one of these test case right from
your execution list let's say you have
mapped multiple test cases under this
execution list
so if you want to exclude one of them
right click and then simply you can
disable it
as soon as you disable it
is going to disable from the execution
list see this is disabled again right
click and you can enable this okay that
way you can enable
and one more
so that is one thing and
let's say if you want to execute our one
more thing so one more thing is if you
want to
refresh or synchronize this particular
test case right click here and there is
an option called sync see if you here
if you right click on your execution
list and click on synchronize what it
will do it will synchronize your later
let's say you made some modifications to
this test cases right
so those changes needs to be reflected
to this execution list so right click
and click on synchronize so that will
bring the latest updated folders okay so
either you can directly drag and drop
your test cases or let's assume I want
to drag and drop this entire folder you
can simply drag and drop your folder
also see this entire folder is dragged
and dropped and if you want to
synchronize this entire folder right
click and you can just synchronize this
folder so what happens all the test
cases under this folder will gets
updated or synchronized with the latest
updates okay so let me delete this one
for now
and one more thing is let's assume I
want to run this execution list multiple
times
so let's drag and drop this folder also
here if you want to if I want to execute
the test case under this folder multiple
times all the disk is under this folder
then I can simply select the folder
and then here I can specify the
repetitions if I want to repeat this as
three times I can repeat this as three
times if I want to repeat this as 4 I
can repeat as 4 so that you can set up
this repetitions at folder level only
not at the sorry and also you can
specify at the
um
test case level but not at the
execution list level okay under this
execution let's say I want to execute
this test case multiple times I can
specify repetitions as two or three in
the same way under this you have
particular folder to be repeated for
multiple times you can specify that as
well okay so now let's delete this again
okay
so that is one thing
and Okay so
let's say our
we have mapped all the test cases that I
want to run as part of this execution
list right now if I want to run this
I need to Simply right click and click
on run
so that will start your test cases okay
and and also
okay see it opened the web browser and
it started running the test cases okay
so we mapped two test cases it's gonna
run two those two test cases as part of
that execution list
foreign
so this is my first test case
okay so it's executed
and then done
and then it's going to start executing
my second test case
see it started executing my second test
case
so it might get failed because of some
issues with that test case but however
let it fail also okay I just failed it
okay I want to show how can we analyze
the test results if you see here under
execution lists it is gonna maintain
your history okay this is my one run
first run
of my first test case and this is my
first run of my second test case right
if you expand this see this is failed
okay so if I want to analyze this double
click on this sorry double click on here
and then you will get
the details see the matching tab was not
found okay so this is what the error I
got right so basically you can
see all the logs
of your execution right and then if you
see here log info out of
two test cases one is passed one is
failed and you can also see what is the
start time of this test case see start
time and the duration right for this
what is the start time and the duration
correct I can see that also and this
test case is totally passed see I can
see all the steps are passed for this
test case
one test one step got failed correct and
if I run this again what happens it's
gonna append new row okay so basically
it maintains entire history of your test
runs for this execution list and for
these test cases okay and also let me
tell you one more thing see for these
execution lists let's say here okay
let's go to execution list if I specify
any test configurations okay so let's go
here
under this test case let's say under
this execution list I have two test
cases correct if I specify browser as
Edge
okay but the actual test case has
configuration
as Chrome okay let's say your actual
test cases as a configuration as Chrome
but if you specify your browser as edge
here what it will do
any time whatever the test configuration
you specified under your execution list
will take a precedence it overrides
overwrites your test case configurations
so basically any configuration
of your execution list will
take a precedence or it will override
the configurations that you specified in
here okay if you specify if you if you
don't specify any test configurations at
execution list level then it follows the
configuration of your test cases okay
hope you all understand the concepts how
to create execution lists
and what are all the different options
that are available to run your execution
list and what are all the options that
is available to make repetitions right
you can repeat your execution test case
execution by providing repetitions right
how can you exclude specific test case
from your execution list right
and then how can you run the test cases
and how can you synchronize your
execution list so that it takes your
up to date our latest stress cases right
all these options you already
uh understand okay
so if you have any queries you can just
leave your queries in the comment box
thank you
[Music]